Carlton E. Morse Script Collection
Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Library of Congress
Carlton E. Morse Script Collection 1939-1952
Morse, Carlton E., 1901-
5 linear feet (15 boxes)
Recorded Sound Reference Center, Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Photocopies of sixty-four radio scripts written by Carlton E. Morse for the detective series Adventures by Morse, I Love a Mystery, and I Love Adventure.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Morse, Carlton E., 1901-
Subjects
Detective and mystery radio programs--United States--Authorship.; Detective and mystery radio programs--United States.; Detectives--Drama.; Long, Doc (Fictitious character); Packard, Jack (Fictitious character); Yorke, Reggie (Fictitious character)
Titles
I love a mystery (Radio program)
Form/Genre
Detective and mystery radio programs.; Photocopies.; Radio scripts.
Administrative Information
Collection Acquisition
The Carlton E. Morse Script Collection was registered and deposited for copyright at the Library of Congress in 1990 and 1991 by the Morse Family Trust. It is housed in the Recorded Sound Reference Center in the Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Library of Congress.
Additions
No further additions to the collection are expected.
Access Restrictions
The Carlton E. Morse Script Collection is open for research.
Biographical Note
Carlton E. Morse (1901-1993) was born in Jennings, Louisiana, in 1901. He and his family moved to Oregon in 1906 following his parents' purchase of a fruit and dairy ranch. After some years, the family relocated to Sacramento, California. Morse attended the University of California at Berkeley but never graduated.
Morse's early career included working as a newspaper writer for the Sacramento Union, covering radio and police news. He wrote for several other newspapers before landing in 1928 at the San Francisco Bulletin. Due to a change in the paper’s ownership, Morse left that job and became a writer for radio station KGO, writing radio musical shows, mystery dramas, and serials. His well-known radio serial, One Man's Family, debuted in 1932 and ran until 1959, becoming one of the longest-running American radio soap operas.
After retiring to Woodside, California, Morse wrote six novels. In 1984, his first wife of sixty years, Patricia De Ball, died. Carlton E. Morse died in 1993 at the age of 91, survived by his second wife, Millie and daughter, Noel.
Scope and Content Note
When I Love a Mystery debuted in 1939, Carlton E. Morse was quite well known as the writer, director, and producer of the popular radio serial One Man's Family. One Man's Family became one of the longest-running American radio soap operas, broadcasting 3,256 episodes from 1932 to 1959. I Love a Mystery, which Morse also wrote, directed, and produced, aired until 1952. Morse created other radio serials including I Love Adventure, China Town Squad, Adventures by Morse, Family Skeleton, and His Honor, the Barber.
The Carlton E. Morse Script Collection, spanning the years 1939 to 1952, consists of photocopies of radio scripts, a few with annotations. It includes four Adventures by Morse scripts, forty-seven I Love a Mystery scripts, and thirteen I Love Adventure scripts, for a total of sixty-four scripts in 105 folders.
Collection Arrangement
The collection is arranged in three series:
Series 1: Adventures by Morse Scripts, 1944
Series 2: I Love a Mystery Scripts, 1939-1944, 1949-1952
Series 3: I Love Adventure Scripts, 1948
Each series is organized by episode title and then chronologically by year and by story number.
http://lccn.loc.gov/2008647467
Container List
- Series 1. Adventures by Morse Scripts, 1944, 6 folders
  Adventures by Morse was a fifty-two-week run of mysteries written by Carlton E. Morse after his series I Love a Mystery was cancelled by NBC. It broadcast as a transcribed syndication from 1944 to 1945 in thirty-minute weekly episodes. The radio series was divided into major stories which ran for ten weeks followed by a three-week story line. The show recounted the adventures of Captain Bart Friday, a San Francisco detective, and his assistant, Skip Turner.
  Elliott Lewis, David Ellis, and Russell Thorson alternately played the role of Captain Friday, while Jack Edwards played Skip Turner.
  - "You'll Be Dead in a Week," undated, Also titled "You'll Be Dead in a Month." (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "A Coffin for the Lady," undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "The City of the Dead," episodes 1-5, 1930 September 26-October 24 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "The City of the Dead," episodes 6-10, 1930 October 31-November 28 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Dead Men Prowl," episodes 1-5, 1931 October 28-November 25 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Dead Men Prowl," episodes 6-10 1931 December 2-December 30 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series 2. I Love a Mystery Scripts, 1939-1944, 1949-1952, 4 linear feet
  I Love a Mystery was the story of three adventurers, Jack Packard, Doc Long, and Reggie Yorke, who wandered the world solving cases for the A-1 Detective Agency. I Love a Mystery first aired on the NBC West Coast network as a daily fifteen-minute serial. In October 1939, Fleishmann's Yeast began sponsoring the program, which now was broadcast nationally. In 1940 it became a thirty-minute weekly program airing Monday evenings on NBC's Blue Network. In 1943 the show changed back to a fifteen-minute serial for CBS and was sponsored by Proctor and Gamble until 1944, when it left the air for five years. In 1949 I Love a Mystery was back on the Mutual network as a fifteen-minute serial, broadcasting weeknights from New York. It ran until 1952.
  The cast included Michael Raffetto, Barton Yarborough, Walter Paterson, and Gloria Blondell as the lead performers during the West Coast run from 1939 to 1944. In New York, Jim Boles, Russell Thorson, Tony Randall, and Mercedes McCambride performed reruns of previous scripts from 1949 until 1952.
  - "The Snake with the Diamond Eyes," chapters 1-6, 1940 April 4-May 9 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "The Snake with the Diamond Eyes," chapters 7-13, 1940 May 9-June 27 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "The Twenty Traitors of Timbuktu," episodes 196-207, 1943 December 17-1944 January 5 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "The Twenty Traitors of Timbuktu," episodes 208-219, 1944 January 6-January 21 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "The Twenty Traitors of Timbuktu," episodes 220-232, 1944 January 24-February 9 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "The Twenty Traitors of Timbuktu," episodes 233-244, 1944 February 10-February 25 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "You Can't Pin a Murder on Nevada," episodes 300-306, 1944 May 15-May 23 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "You Can't Pin a Murder on Nevada," episodes 307-314, 1944 May 24-June 2 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "The Corpse in Compartment C, Car 76," episodes 315-319, 1944 June 5-June 9 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "The Thing Wouldn't Die," episodes 320-328, 1944 June 12-June 23 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "The Thing Wouldn't Die," episodes 329-338, 1944 June 26-July 7 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "Portrait of a Murderess," episodes 428-437, 1944 November 10-November 23 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "Portrait of a Murderess," episodes 438-447, 1944 November 24-December 7 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "Bury Your Dead, Arizona," episode 1; episodes 235-240, 1949 November 21; 1939 December 12-December 19 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "Bury Your Dead, Arizona," episodes 241-248, 1939 December 20-December 29 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "The Million Dollar Curse," story number 4, episodes 1-7, 1949 December 12-December 20 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "The Million Dollar Curse," story number 4, episodes 8-15, 1949 December 21-December 30 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "The Temple of Vampires," story number 5, episodes 1-10, 1950 January 2-January 13 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "The Temple of Vampires," story number 5, episodes 11-20, 1950 January 16-January 27 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - "The Battle of the Century," story number 6, episodes 1-9, 1950 January 30-February 9 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - "The Battle of the Century," story number 6, episodes 10-22, 1950 February 10-February 22 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - "The Tropics Don't Call It Murder," story number 7, episodes 1-8, 1950 February 23-March 6 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - "The Tropics Don't Call It Murder," story number 7, episodes 9-17, 1950 March 7-March 17 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "The Tropics Don't Call It Murder," story number 7, episodes 18-26, 1950 March 20-March 30 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "The Case of the Nevada Man Killer," story number 8, episodes 1-12, 1950 March 31-April 17 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - "The Case of the Nevada Man Killer," story number 8, episodes 13-25, 1950 April 18-May 4 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - "The Turn of the Wheel," story number 9, episodes 1-10, 1950 May 5-May 18 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - "The Turn of the Wheel," story number 9, episodes 11-20, 1950 May 19-June 1 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - "The Blue Phantom Murders," story number 10, episodes 1-7, 1950 June 2-June 12 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - "The Blue Phantom Murders," story number 10, episodes 8-15, 1950 June 13-June 22 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - "The Flight to Death," story number 12, episodes 1-7, 1950 July 30-August 8 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - "The Flight to Death," story number 12, episodes 8-15, 1950 August 9-August 18 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - "Murder in Turquoise Pass," story number 13, episodes 1-7, 1950 August 21-August 29 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - "Murder in Turquoise Pass," story number 13, episodes 8-15, 1950 August 30-September 8 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - "Whose Body Got Buried?" story number 14, episodes 1-7, 1950 September 11-September 19 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - "Whose Body Got Buried?" story number 14, episodes 8-15, 1950 September 20-September 29 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - "Escapade of the Desert Hag," story number 15, episode 1; episodes 92-97, 1950 October 2; 1939 May 23-May 30 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - "Escapade of the Desert Hag," story number 15, episodes 98-105, 1939 May 31-June 9 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - "Trouble at Sea," story number 17, episodes 1-6, 1950 November 13-November 20 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - "Trouble at Sea," story number 17, episodes 7-12, November 21-November 28 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - "Incident Concerning Death," story number 18, episodes 1-7, 1950 November 29-December 7 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - "Incident Concerning Death," story number 18, episodes 8-15, 1950 December 8-December 19 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "The Case of the Roxy Mob," story number 19, episodes 1-7, 1950 December 20-December 28 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "The Case of the Roxy Mob," story number 19, episodes 8-14, 1950 December 29-1951 January 8 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - "The Case of the Transplanted Castle," story number 20, episodes 1-9, 1951 January 9-January 19 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "The Case of the Transplanted Castle," story number 20, episodes 10-18, 1951 January 22-February 1 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - "Murder on February Island," story number 21, episodes 1-9, 1951 February 2-February 14 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - "Murder on February Island," story number 21, episodes 10-18, 1951 February 15-February 27 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - "The Monster in the Mansion," story number 22, episodes 1-11, 1951 February 28-March 14 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - "The Monster in the Mansion," story number 22, episodes 12-23, 1951 March 15-March 30 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - "Eight Kinds of Murder," story number 23, episodes 1-8, 1951 April 2-April 11 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - "Eight Kinds of Murder," story number 23, episodes 9-16, 1951 April 12-April 23 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - "Secret Passage to Death," story number 24, episodes 1-10, 1951 April 24-May 7 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - "Secret Passage to Death," story number 24, episodes 11-20, 1951 May 8-May 21 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - "Terror at Frozen Corpse Lodge," story number 25, episodes 1-9, 1951 May 22-June 1 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - "Terror at Frozen Corpse Lodge," story number 25, episodes 10-18, 1951 June 4-June 14 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - "The Pirate Loot of the Island of Skulls," story number 26, episodes 1-12, 1951 June 15-July 2 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - "The Pirate Loot of the Island of Skulls," story number 26, episodes 13-24, 1951 July 3-July 18 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - "Brooks Kidnapping," story number 27, episodes 1-7, 1951 July 19-July 27 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "Brooks Kidnapping," story number 27, episodes 8-15, 1951 July 30-August 8 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - "Murder Hollywood Style," story number 28, episodes 1-7, 1951 August 9-August 17 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - "Murder Hollywood Style," story number 28, episodes 8-15, 1951 August 20-August 29 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - "The Gird in the Gilded Cage," story number 29, episodes 1-7, 1951 August 30-September 7 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - "The Gird in the Gilded Cage," story number 29, episodes 8-15, 1951 September 10-September 19 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - "Blood on the Cat," story number 30, episodes 1-10, 1951 September 20-October 3 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - "Blood on the Cat," story number 30, episodes 11-20, 1951 October 4-October 17 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - "The Case of the Terrified Comedian," story number 31, episodes 1-10, 1951 October 18-October 31 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - "The Case of the Terrified Comedian," story number 31, episodes 11-21, 1951 November 1-November 16 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - "The Killer of the Circle M," story number 32, episodes 1-10, 1951 November 19-November 30 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - "The Killer of the Circle M," story number 32, episodes 11-20, 1951 December 2-December 14 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - "Murder Is the Word for It," story number 33, episodes 1-7, 1951 December 17-December 25 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - "Murder Is the Word for It," story number 33, episodes 8-15, 1951 December 26-1952 January 4 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - "Stairway to the Sun," story number 34, episodes 1-10, 1952 January 7-January 18 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - "Stairway to the Sun," story number 34, episodes 11-20, 1952 January 21-February 1 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - "Stairway to the Sun," story number 34, episodes 21-30, 1952 February 4-February 15 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - "The Graves of Whamperjaw, Texas," story number 35, episodes 1-7, 1952 February 18-February 26 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - "The Graves of Whamperjaw, Texas," story number 35, episodes 8-15, 1952 February 27-March 7 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - "The Decapitation of Jefferson Monk," story number 36, episodes 1-12, 1952 March 10-March 23 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - "The Decapitation of Jefferson Monk," story number 36, episodes 13-25, 1952 March 26-April 11 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - "The Hermit of San Felipe, Atabapo," story number 38, episodes 1-10, 1952 May 19-May 30 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - "The Hermit of San Felipe, Atabapo," story number 38, episodes 11-20, 1952 June 2-June 13 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - "The Deadly Sin of Sir Richard Coyle," story number 39, episodes 1-7, 1952 June 16-June 24 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - "The Deadly Sin of Sir Richard Coyle," story number 39, episodes 8-15, 1952 June 25-July 4 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - "The Man Who Hated to Shave," story number 40, episodes 1-10, 1952 July 7-July 18 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - "The African Jungle Mystery," story number 41, episodes 1-10, 1952 July 14-August 1 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - "The African Jungle Mystery," story number 41, episodes 11-20, 1952 August 4-August 15 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - "The Cobra King Strikes Back," story number 42, episodes 1-10, 1952 September 1-September 12 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - "The Cobra King Strikes Back," story number 42, episodes 11-20, 1952 September 15-September 26 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - "The Widow with the Amputation," story number 43, episodes 1-10, 1952 September 30-October 13 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - "The Widow with the Amputation," story number 43, episodes 11-20, 1952 October 14-October 27 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - "I Am a Destroyer of Women," story number 44, episodes 1-7, 1952 October 28-November 6 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - "I Am a Destroyer of Women," story number 44, episodes 8-15, 1952 November 10-November 19 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - "The Bride of the Werewolf," story number 45, episodes 1-7, 1952 November 20-November 28 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - "The Bride of the Werewolf," story number 45, episodes 8-15, 1952 December 1-December 10 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - "Find Elsa Holberg, Dead or Alive," story number 46, episodes 1-6, 1952 December 11-December 18 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - "Find Elsa Holberg, Dead or Alive," story number 46, episodes 7-12, 1952 December 19-December 26 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Series 3. I Love Adventure Scripts, 1948, 3 folders
  I Love Adventure, also written and directed by Carlton Morse, continued the story of the characters Jack, Doc, and Reggie from I Love a Mystery. It was broadcast in thirteen episodes as a thirty-minute serial on ABC in 1948 on Sundays from April 25 to July 18. Actors Michael Raffetto and Barton Yarborough played their original roles as Jack and Doc, and Tom Collins played Reggie.
  - 1948 April 25-May 16 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    "China Coast Incident," 1948 April 25, episode 1
    "Great Air Mail Robbery," 1948 May 2, incident 2
    "The Devil's Sanctuary," 1948 May 9, incident 3
    "The Pearl of Great Price," 1948 May 16, incident 4
  - 1948 May 23-June 20 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    "The Hundred Million Dollar Manhunt," 1948 May 23, incident 5
    "The Girl's Finishing School Kidnapping," 1948 May 30, incident 6
    "But Grandma, What Big Teeth You Have," 1948 June 6, incident 7
    "The Man with the Third Green Eye," 1948 June 13, incident 8
    "Girl in the Street," 1948 June 20, incident 9
  - 1948 June 27-July 18 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    "The Kwan-Moon Dagger," 1948 June 27, incident 10
    "The Assignment with a Displaced Person," 1948 July 4, incident 11
    "The Hearse on the Highway," 1948 July 11, incident 12
    "The Ambassador Ricardo Santos Affair," 1948 July 18, incident 13